<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Career on KernelCurry</title><link>https://kernelcurry.com/career/</link><description>Recent content in Career on KernelCurry</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 18:16:09 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kernelcurry.com/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kittyhawk.io - Director of Engineering</title><link>https://kernelcurry.com/career/kittyhawk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kernelcurry.com/career/kittyhawk/</guid><description>As the first full-time engineering employee, my core functions were to organize, scale, and manage an engineering department, while also serving as a high-functioning IC. In my time at Kittyhawk, I accomplished that and more, including working extensively with the FAA, leading the product vision and roadmap, and redesigning our applications to fit the enterprise sector.
Below are just a few select highlights: Built, scaled, and led multi-platform, execution-focused engineering and product teams, with remote and local employees.</description></item><item><title>Levers - Lead Engineer</title><link>https://kernelcurry.com/career/levers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kernelcurry.com/career/levers/</guid><description>Levers creates prioritized tasks using existing analytics to increase revenue and customer acquisition, as well as, forecasting key business metrics and areas for improvements. Advanced tools enable campaign and performance improvements.</description></item><item><title>Stitch Labs - Senior Software Engineer</title><link>https://kernelcurry.com/career/stitch-labs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kernelcurry.com/career/stitch-labs/</guid><description>Stitch Labs is a leading inventory management system for rapidly growing eCommerce retailers. Stitch Labs empowers retailers to control their operations through enhanced inventory visibility and accuracy, alongside streamlined workflows to meet the most complex and demanding operational challenges. Stitch Labs works with major eCommerce and fulfillment providers to offer a seamless solution.
Major Accomplishments Collaborated cross-functionally to accelerate development cycles and ensure successful releases. Led team responsible for delivering a subscription model that enabled 3x annual recurring revenue growth.</description></item><item><title>VUURR - Engineer</title><link>https://kernelcurry.com/career/vuurr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kernelcurry.com/career/vuurr/</guid><description>Vuurr specializes in digital marketing campaigns and custom application development for clients ranging from startups &amp;amp; small businesses to $10+ billion enterprises.
Custom (PHP) Development Projects: Customer loyalty and customer marketing solution for the tire and service industry. Solution for an international training company empowering users to discover &amp;amp; register for certification-specific courses, and enabling instructors to award performance-based course credits. Internal end-to-end order tracking application for an eCommerce custom print apparel company Dynamic internal product catalog for a leading dairy producer Wordpress Projects: Built United States governor campaign website Created custom theme, implemented &amp;amp; managed plug-ins, and rebuilt food &amp;amp; crafts brand website with over 1.</description></item></channel></rss>