<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Career on KernelCurry</title><link>https://kernelcurry.com/career/</link><description>Recent content in Career on KernelCurry</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kernelcurry.com/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kittyhawk.io - Director of Engineering</title><link>https://kernelcurry.com/career/kittyhawk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kernelcurry.com/career/kittyhawk/</guid><description>&lt;p>As the first full-time engineering employee, my core functions were to organize, scale, and manage an engineering department, while also serving as a high-functioning IC. In my time at Kittyhawk, I accomplished that and more, including working extensively with the FAA, leading the product vision and roadmap, and redesigning our applications to fit the enterprise sector.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="below-are-just-a-few-select-highlights">Below are just a few select highlights:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Built, scaled, and led multi-platform, execution-focused engineering and product teams, with remote and local employees.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Secured exclusive FAA B4UFLY application contract, an application that notifies and informs recreational drone pilots on current airspace restrictions in their local areas across the United States.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Became an FAA-approved UAS Service Supplier, allowing us to provide LAANC (Low Altitude Authorization and Notification Capability) Authorizations to commercial and recreational drone operators enabling them to comply with federal drone regulations.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Contributed to multiple patents in the airspace industry.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Refactored our subscription &amp;amp; billing models to account for custom contracts within our sales organization.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rebuilt iOS and Android applications from the ground up to provide a more stable service to our safety-centric core customers (Insurance, Energy, Transportation, Government, Law Enforcement).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Built and executed company-wide quarterly OKRs, aligning the entire company on major strategic initiatives.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Worked cross-functionally on all product updates and releases.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Led company-wide SOC 2 Type 1 audit and certification process.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Levers - Lead Engineer</title><link>https://kernelcurry.com/career/levers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kernelcurry.com/career/levers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Levers takes your aggregated digital marketing data and delivers a complete reporting and forecasting solution in a beautiful, easy to use interface. Built for the digital marketer, the Levers data explorer is your solution for high-level analysis and forecasting. Borrowing the best features from the analytics products you use every day with nearly unlimited scalability, Levers makes it easy to build reports accessible by anyone from technical analysts to executives.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stitch Labs - Senior Software Engineer</title><link>https://kernelcurry.com/career/stitch-labs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kernelcurry.com/career/stitch-labs/</guid><description>&lt;p>Stitch Labs is a leading inventory management system for rapidly growing eCommerce retailers. Stitch Labs empowers retailers to control their operations through enhanced inventory visibility and accuracy, alongside streamlined workflows to meet the most complex and demanding operational challenges. Stitch Labs works with major eCommerce and fulfillment providers to offer a seamless solution.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="major-accomplishments">Major Accomplishments&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Collaborated cross-functionally to accelerate development cycles and ensure successful releases.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Led team responsible for delivering a subscription model that enabled 3x annual recurring revenue growth.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Designed and built an underlying migration framework enabling the transition from a database management provider to an in-house solution.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Overhauled customer acquisition funnel, providing new insights into customer journey lifecycle, and identifying opportunities for sales.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Architected and implemented 3rd party fulfillment integration allowing partners to manage orders in real-time at the warehouse level.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Built a solution giving the customer support team the ability to create unique customer reports and data visualizations via MySQL queries.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Primary Stack Stack:&lt;/strong> &lt;em>Linux, NGINX, MySQL, PHP (Laravel)&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>VUURR - Engineer</title><link>https://kernelcurry.com/career/vuurr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kernelcurry.com/career/vuurr/</guid><description>&lt;p>Vuurr specializes in digital marketing campaigns and custom application development for clients ranging from startups &amp;amp; small businesses to $10+ billion enterprises.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="custom-php-development-projects">Custom (PHP) Development Projects:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Customer loyalty and customer marketing solution for the tire and service industry.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Solution for an international training company empowering users to discover &amp;amp; register for certification-specific courses, and enabling instructors to award performance-based course credits.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Internal end-to-end order tracking application for an eCommerce custom print apparel company&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dynamic internal product catalog for a leading dairy producer&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="wordpress-projects">Wordpress Projects:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Built United States governor campaign website&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Created custom theme, implemented &amp;amp; managed plug-ins, and rebuilt food &amp;amp; crafts brand website with over 1.5 million unique monthly sessions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>